[Evans] I think there are 3 main themes that really pervade the course
我认为有3个主题
that we've seen over and over again,
真正渗透我们反复看到的课程
but I haven't mentioned them explicitly until now.
但到目前为止 我还没有明显提到
These are themes that aren't just pervasive throughout this course
这些主题不仅仅在贯穿这一课程
but are pervasive throughout all computer science.
但整个计算机科学中也是普及的
The first one is abstraction.
第一个是抽象
Abstraction is all about hiding details.
抽象就是隐藏详细信息
The point of abstraction is to make it so you can have 1 thing that is used
抽象的意思是进行抽象化 这样你可以有一样
in many different ways, and you can use it
通过许多不同方式使用过的东西 你可以使用它
without necessarily understanding all the details behind it.
不一定要理解它所有的详细信息
We've seen lots and lots of examples of abstraction in this class.
我们在这一课程中看到了大量此类抽象的例子
The most important one is procedural abstraction.
最重要的一个是程序抽象
We can write 1 procedure, use it to do lots of different things
我们可以编写一个过程 用它来做很多不同的事情
depending on what the inputs are, and when we use that procedure
取决于输入的内容 和我们使用该过程的时候
we don't need to know exactly what sequence of instructions will execute.
我们不需要知道具体会执行什么样的指令序列
What we know is what the procedure does.
我们知道过程的用途
The second main theme is universality.
第二个主题是通用性
We talked about this early in the class
我们之前在课程中讨论过
about how computers are universal machines.
计算机如何是通用机器
I want to show you how much better I've gotten at drawing.
我想向你展示我在绘图方面有了多大长进
If you thought my drawing of a toaster in Unit 1 was not recognizable,
如果你认不出我在第一单元画的烤面包机
I hope you can see how much better I can do now.
我希望你可以看到我现在画得要好得多了
This is a toaster, and a toaster is very different from a computer.
这是一个烤面包机 烤面包机和计算机截然不同
A computer is a universal machine.
计算机是一种通用的机器
We've seen lots of examples of how a computer is universal--
我们见过许多例子 证明一台计算机是如何通用的——
that we only need a few simple constructs to be able to define every possible program.
我们只需要几个简单的构造就可以定义每个可能的程序
We saw that if we had a way to make decisions--
我们看到了 如果我们有一种做决定的方式
and we saw we have that with if in Python;
我们看到了在 Python 中 if 可以做到这一点
we saw that if we have a way to keep track of things--
如果我们有一种方法跟踪事情——
and in Python we can do that using variables and data;
在 Python 中 我们可以使用变量和数据
and if we have a way to keep going--
如果我们有一种方式继续——
and we first saw that using while--with a while loop we can make something keep going
我们首先看到使用 while——用 while 循环 我们可以让事情继续
as long as we want.
只要我们想的话
But in fact, we don't even need while.
但事实上 我们甚至不需要 while
We could do that with procedures, and that's what we saw with recursive definitions
我们可以通过过程就可以了 这就是我们所看到的
in Unit 6.
第6单元的递归定义
Once we have those 3 things, we can write any computer program.
一旦我们有了这3个东西 我们可以编写任何计算机程序
So we have much more power with a computer than we do with a toaster.
因此 计算机的力量比烤面包机大得多
The final major theme I want to summarize as our third main theme
最后一个主题 也就是我想总结的第三个主题
is one we've already mentioned here.
我们已经提到过了
It's recursive definitions.
就是递归定义
We introduced those explicitly in Unit 6,
在第6单元中 我们清楚介绍过了
but you saw them many times before that.
但是你在那之前也见过很多次
The first time you saw them was actually in Unit 1.
第一次你看见递归定义实际上是在第一单元
We saw these rules that said we can make an expression
我们看到了这些规则 规定我们能生成一个表达式
by taking another expression, using the plus operator,
通过采取另一个表达式 使用加号运算符
and combining it with another expression.
并将它与另一个表达式结合起来
That was not enough by itself for a recursive definition.
这本身对于递归定义还不够
We also needed a base case.
我们还需要一个递归的基础
We saw a base case, like we can have an expression that's a number.
我们看到了递归的基础 比如我们可以有一个表达式是一个数字
So the big idea here is that with very simple rules we can define infinitely many things
这里的主要意思就是有了非常简单的规则 我们可以无限地定义很多东西
and very complex things by using rules to define things
通过使用规则 定义非常复杂的东西
in terms of simpler versions of themselves.
用自身的缩小版进行定义